# **Amy Gurski**

https://www.linkedin.com/in/amygurski/

3336 Stockholm Road Cleveland, OH 44120 (216) 235-1052 amygurski@gmail.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Self-motivated engineer whose career is focused on combining technical expertise with customer service. Colleagues would describe me as highly organized, proactive, and detail-oriented. I enjoy the process and challenge of expanding my knowledge and skillset.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# FORBERG SCIENTIFIC, Cleveland, Ohio

# **Inside Sales Manager**

MAY 2018 - DECEMBER 2019

- Lead the inside sales teams in Ohio and Pennsylvania
- Generate quotes and provide customer support for a wide range of process automation requirements
- Integral part of team which launched the new company Sharepoint

## **ENDRESS+HAUSER**, Manchester, United Kingdom

## **Inside Sales Manager**

AUG 2010 - AUG 2017

- Lead, mentor, and coach inside sales team to achieve target of \$25m
- Advise customers on the best fit instrumentation for level, flow, pressure, temperature, and liquid analysis measurements
- Build relationships with end users, OEMs, and distributors
- Generate quotes and follow-up with customers to secure orders
- Tailor proposal based on industry requirements, primarily food & beverage, pharmaceutical, chemical, oil & gas, and water & wastewater
- Received record breaking marine industry order of \$750,000
- Promoted from Supervisor (2014) and Inside Sales Engineer (2012)

#### **SKILLS**

Soft Skills

Leadership, verbal & written communication, problem solving, embracing change, multitasking, team building

Office skills

SAP, Salesforce, Incoterms, Advanced Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, Powerpoint), Outlook, Lotus Notes

Technical skills

Technical writing,
project management,
hazardous areas,
surface metrology,
selection and sizing of
process
instrumentation,
Piping and
Instrumentation
Diagrams (P&IDs)

Amy Gurski page 1 of 2

# ZYGO CORPORATION, Middlefield, Connecticut

## Senior Applications Engineer

JAN 2005 - SEPT 2009

- Mentor and train applications engineers
- Interface with customers in support of sales and service
- Provide technical support and training on metrology equipment
- Test customer samples on optical profiler
- Develop bespoke applications for automating measurement systems
- Generate technical reports and presentations to aid system sales
- Conduct product demonstrations
- Promoted from Applications Engineer (2008)

#### PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

- Responsive Web Design Certificate from freeCodeCamp JULY 2019
- Good Manufacturing Practice (GMP) Fundamentals SEPT 2016
- CompEx Certificate for Foundation in Hazardous Awareness OCT 2015
- Leadership Academy MAY 2015
- Customer Plus training for Customer Service Excellence JUNE 2015
- Business and Technology Education Council Level 3 Award in Management from Stockport College — SEPT 2013
- National Vocational Qualification Level 2 in Team Leading MAR 2013
- Professional Engineer Intern (EIT) license from Connecticut FEB 2009
- Introduction to structured programming using C# course at Springfield Technical Community College — MAY 2008
- Summer in Optics at University of Rochester MAY 2006

#### **EDUCATION**

# **BOSTON UNIVERSITY**, Boston, Massachusetts

## Master of Science, Global Manufacturing

SEPT 2002 - SEPT 2004

Sponsored by the Fraunhofer Institute. Included one year internship in Germany.

Thesis: Selective laser sintering of borosilicate glass

## Bachelor of Science, Electrical Engineering

SEPT 1998 - MAY 2002

Senior Design Project: System for detection of phased array warning system

Amy Gurski page 2 of 2